{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tina Turner","incorrectAnswers":["Britney Spears","Lady Gaga","Toni Braxton"],"question":"Whose real name is Annie Mae Bullock?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dream Theater","incorrectAnswers":["Jars of Clay","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American progressive metal band released the studio album 'Octavarium'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tripoli","incorrectAnswers":["Managua","Yaren District","Quito"],"question":"What is the capital city of Libya?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mobil","incorrectAnswers":["Shell","Chevron","BP"],"question":"Which oil company did Exxon merge with in 1999?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["Jane Eyre","Sense and Sensibility","Wuthering Heights"],"question":"In which book does 'Jane Bennet' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventure of the Copper Beeches'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Germany","Kingdom of the Netherlands"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Norway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Kansas City Chiefs","incorrectAnswers":["Kansas City Bears","Kansas City Mariners","Kansas City Pistons"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Kansas City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Evil","incorrectAnswers":["Shame","Jewellery","Mystery"],"question":"What did Pandora release when she opened the box?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which singer released the album 'Rebel Heart'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Muse","incorrectAnswers":["Tears for Fears","Bullet For My Valentine","Enter Shikari"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Origin of Symmetry'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Halle Berry","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in both X-Men: Days of Future Past and Die Another Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Elton John","Sting"],"question":"Which British musician released the studio album 'Hunky Dory'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Wait a minute, wait a minute. You ain't heard nothin' yet!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I am a golden god!\"","\"You had me at hello.\"","\"Gentlemen, you can't fight in here! This is the War Room!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Jazz Singer'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"First Test Tube Baby","incorrectAnswers":["First Woman in Space","Oldest Human Being","Solved Fermat's Last Theorem"],"question":"Why Is Louise Brown Famous?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henry IV","incorrectAnswers":["King Lear","Macbeth","Romeo and Juliet"],"question":"Owen Glendower was a historic figure who appeared as a rebel leader in which of Shakespeare's plays?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mark David Chapman","incorrectAnswers":["J. D. Salinger","Lee Harvey Oswald","John Wilkes Booth"],"question":"Who Was Responsible For The Assassination Of John Lennon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Byzantine Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The Holy Roman Empire","The Ottoman Empire","The Mongol Empire"],"question":"The fall of Constantinople in 1453 marked the end of which empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dancers","incorrectAnswers":["Actors","Authors","Painters"],"question":"What is the profession of Michael Flatley and Martha Graham?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Jordan","Israel"],"question":"In which country is the city of Izmir?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Reed","incorrectAnswers":["The Bucket","The Tap","The Curl"],"question":"What Is The Sound Producing Equipment Element Of Many Woodwind Instrument Called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"10","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","0"],"question":"An earthquake with a magnitude of 8 on the Richter scale has waves that are how many times larger than one with a magnitude of 7?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ayn Rand","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Mikhail Bulgakov","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Atlas Shrugged'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Paul McCartney","Sting"],"question":"Which English singer-songwriter released the song 'Rocket Man'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Guinness","incorrectAnswers":["Stella Artois","Budweiser","Fosters"],"question":"Which beer brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Good things come to those who wait'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which band includes 'Mick Jagger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Gymnastics","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","Rugby Union","Football"],"question":"With which sport is Larisa Latynina associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"10 K","incorrectAnswers":["100 K","1,000 K","10,000 K"],"question":"What is the approximate temperature of an interstellar gas cloud?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Verivorst","incorrectAnswers":["Cou Cou and Flying Fish","Plov","Pad Thai"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Estonia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michelangelo","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo","Raphael","Donatello"],"question":"Which great Renaissance figure had the surname Buonarroti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kate Winslet","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Kirsten Dunst","Sandra Bæ Hovedr"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including The Reader and Finding Neverland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Age of Innocence","incorrectAnswers":["The House of Mirth","Heart of Darkness","On the Road"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Newland Archer'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Phil Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Mario Andretti","Lance Stroll","Dan Gurney"],"question":"Who was the first american to win the Formula 1 championship?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Khaled Hosseini","incorrectAnswers":["Nathaniel Hawthorne","Robert E. Howard","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Kite Runner'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in thermometers, thermostats, barometers","incorrectAnswers":["It is used as an ingredient in baking.","It is used as an ingredient in the production of glass, bricks, and ceramics.","It is used in disinfectants and antiseptics."],"question":"What is the chemical mercury often used for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Fellowship of the Ring'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Nine","Black"],"question":"In French, what is the meaning of the word 'rouge'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Japan ","incorrectAnswers":["India","Italy","Brazil"],"question":"Which country does one associate with 'Kasutera'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Quatre","incorrectAnswers":["Quattro","Vier","Sept"],"question":"In French, what is the word for for 'four'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bratislava","incorrectAnswers":["Conakry","Prague","Zagreb"],"question":"What is the capital city of Slovakia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Jailhouse Rock","incorrectAnswers":["All Shook Up","Hound Dog","Love Me Tender"],"question":"Which Elvis song has the lyrics 'Everybody in the whole cell block was dancin' to the ...'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","China","North Korea"],"question":"Which country was declared a socialist nation by its prime minister on May Day, 1961?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1933","incorrectAnswers":["1945","1919","1955"],"question":"When did the Weimar Republic of Germany get replaced by the Third Reich?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Absolute zero","incorrectAnswers":["Freezing point","Boiling point","The point of no return"],"question":"What scientific term refers to a temperature of -273 Celsius?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luxembourg","incorrectAnswers":["Veduz","Brest","Bruges"],"question":"What's the capital of Luxembourg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Humanism","incorrectAnswers":["Materialism","Existentialism","Positivism"],"question":"What is the name of the political philosophy that developed during the Renaissance?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Van Halen","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the song 'Jump'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Shaw","incorrectAnswers":["James Cagney","Orson Welles","Dennis Hopper"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Captain Quint in Jaws?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Motorola","incorrectAnswers":["Sony","Samsung","Nokia"],"question":"'Hello Moto' is a slogan associated with which communications brand?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mel Gibson","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Douglas","Al Pacino","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor played the role of \"Mad\" Max Rockatansky in Mad Max?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Tubular pasta","Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is radiatori?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"John Dos Passos","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Jordan","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'U.S.A.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ZZ Top","incorrectAnswers":["AC/DC","Metallica","Guns N' Roses"],"question":"Which rock band's hits include \"Gimme All Your Lovin\" and \"Sharp Dressed Man\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"To Kill A Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["The Maltese Falcon","Post Office","The Power and the Glory"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Scout Finch'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Baroque","incorrectAnswers":["Impressionism","Cubism","Realism"],"question":"The 17th century saw the rise of which type of art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Czech Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Ecuador","Iraq","Egypt"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Cesky Krumlov?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Philips","incorrectAnswers":["Panasonic","Viewsonic","Sony"],"question":"Which Dutch Company Began Marketing Compact Disc Players In 1982?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Southeast Asia","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Central Asia","North America"],"question":"From which part of the world do bananas originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovenia","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Singapore","Sierra Leone"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.si' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Miami Heat","incorrectAnswers":["Miami Braves","Miami Sounders","Miami Marlins"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Miami?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"West Germany","incorrectAnswers":["The Soviet Union","Italy","Austria"],"question":"From 1949 to 1963, Konrad Adenauer served as the first chancellor of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dan Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Donna Leon","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Angels & Demons'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brasilia","incorrectAnswers":["São Paulo","Rio de Janeiro","Manaus"],"question":"What is the capital city of Brazil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Indian summer","incorrectAnswers":["Mercury summer","Roman summer","Alaska summer"],"question":"What is the name given to a heat wave that occurs in autumn?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Laika","incorrectAnswers":["Bella","Svetlana","Fido"],"question":"Who was the first dog in space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Art Nouveau","Cubism","Baroque"],"question":"The painting \"Bal du Moulin de la Galette\" by Pierre-Auguste Renoir is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gerard Butler","incorrectAnswers":["Hugh Jackman","Robert Redford","Jim Carrey"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Tomorrow Never Dies and Watchmen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Labours of Hercules'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kuala Lumpur","incorrectAnswers":["Luanda","Doha","Kampala"],"question":"What is the capital city of Malaysia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Guglielmo Marconi","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Morse","Alexander Graham Bell","Michael Faraday"],"question":"Who first transmitted radio signals across the Atlantic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Classicism","incorrectAnswers":["Aesthetics","Romanticism","Baroque"],"question":"Which artistic style refers to the following of principles of Ancient Greek and Roman art?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Brain","incorrectAnswers":["Lungs","Heart","Liver"],"question":"In which organ is your \"hypothalmus\" located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Niger–Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Turkic","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Yoruba' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Jack","A Billy","A Drake"],"question":"What is a male rat known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Adrian Monk","incorrectAnswers":["Father Father","Monkus Punkus","The Monk"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Tony Shalhoub on the show 'Monk'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ants","incorrectAnswers":["Wine","Water","Algae"],"question":"What is Formicology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ricotta","incorrectAnswers":["Feta","Gouda","Mozzarella"],"question":"What type of cheese would you be most likely to find in a cheesecake?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Copper & Tin","incorrectAnswers":["Iron & Copper","Iron & Zinc","Aluminium & Zinc"],"question":"From What Metals Is Brass Made?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Willow","incorrectAnswers":["Birch","Elm","Cypress"],"question":"Aspirin was originally obtained from the bark of which tree?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Baked Alaska","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"What is the name of a dessert where a sponge is filled with ice cream and topped with meringue?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Philosopher, author of Social Contract","incorrectAnswers":["Philosopher and mathematician who famously said “I think, therefore I am.”","Greek philosopher and polymath","French military leader who conquered much of Western Europe."],"question":"Which of the following describes Jean-Jacques Rousseau?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","The Beach Boys","The Who"],"question":"Which band's '1962-1966' and '1967-1970' albums sold 13 million copies and 14 million copies respectively?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gone with the Wind","incorrectAnswers":["The Fall of the King","All Quiet on the Western Front","A Tale of Two Cities"],"question":"In which book does 'Scarlett O'Hara' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Black","Two"],"question":"In Italian, what is the meaning of the word 'nove'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Philippines","Tonga","Belize"],"question":"Montevideo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ludwig Wittgenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Socrates","Albert Camus","Democritus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'I don’t know why we are here, but I’m pretty sure it is not in order to enjoy ourselves'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neoclassicism","incorrectAnswers":["Dutch Golden Age","Crystal Cubism","Primitivism"],"question":"The painting \"Napoleon crossing the Alps\" by Jacques-Louis David is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Old Curiosity Shop'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A colony","incorrectAnswers":["A covey","A sedge","A pace"],"question":"What is the word for a group of gulls?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Foxtrot","incorrectAnswers":["Forget","Fail","Felicity"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter F?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Three Mile Island","incorrectAnswers":["Chernobyl","Fukushima","Jaslovské Bohunice"],"question":"In March 1979, where did a major nuclear accident occur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Haka","incorrectAnswers":["Tango","Flamenco","Salsa"],"question":"What is the name of the ceremonial war dance of the Maori people of New Zealand?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harry S. Truman","incorrectAnswers":["James Polk","Herbert Hoover","Grover Cleveland"],"question":"Who was the 33rd president of the USA, in term during the period 1945–1953?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Zacharias Janssen","incorrectAnswers":["Marie Curie","Francis Crick","Nikola Tesla"],"question":"Who developed the first microscope?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Thomas Dolby","incorrectAnswers":["T'Pau","Men Without Hats","C.W. McCall"],"question":"'She Blinded Me With Science' was a one hit wonder in 1983 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Shah Jahan","incorrectAnswers":["Ahmad Khan","Shah Khan","Genghis Khan"],"question":"Who built the Taj Mahal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colombia","incorrectAnswers":["Cote d'Ivoire","Pakistan","Kazakhstan"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"What I Am","incorrectAnswers":["Turning Japanese","Rebirth of Slick (Cool Like Dat)","Electric Avenue"],"question":"Edie Brickell & New Bohemians had a one hit wonder in 1986 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Finland","Portugal"],"question":"Basel is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},